Carolina Power and Light Photograph Collection PHC.68
State Archives of North Carolina
- African American Workers Plowing Cotton, Tucker Estate, Near Raleigh, N.C c. 1912. Two African American men are seen plowing behind two mules under tower number 688 of the Yadkin River Power Company's 100,000 volt line at the Durham Method Section. Tucker Estate, near Raleigh, NC c. 1912, PhC.68.1.200; Carolina Power and Light
- African American Workers Picking Cotton, Raleigh, N. C., c. 1923. African American (approximately 12 men and women) workers are seen picking cotton in a field at an unidentified location near Raleigh, NC. c. 1923, PhC.68.1.201; Carolina Power and Light
- Classes in Session, Vocational-Ag School, Clinton, N.C., 1954., PhC.68.1.202.1-12; Carolina Power and Light
  - Eugene Laycock and W. E. Hamilton (right) are seen using a cut away water pump to demonstrate how the machine works., PhC.68.1.202.7; Carolina Power and Light
  - Eugene Laycock and W. E. Hamilton (right) are seen using a cut away water pump to demonstrate how the machine works., PhC.68.1.202.8; Carolina Power and Light
  - W. E. Hamilton and Eugene Laycock (right) are seen standing against a truck with demonstration pumps mounted in the back., PhC.68.1.202.9; Carolina Power and Light
  - E. Bruce Paddock of Goulds Pumps demonstrates on cutaway pump., PhC.68.1.202.10; Carolina Power and Light
  - E. Bruce Paddock of Goulds Pumps demonstrates on cutaway pump., PhC.68.1.202.11; Carolina Power and Light
  - Left to right, NC State professor of agricultural education L. O. Armstrong, James H. McBrayer of Virginia Electric and Power, and Eugene Laycock of CP&L. They are standing in front of a truck containing five types of water pumps designed for farm use., PhC.68.1.202.12; Carolina Power and Light
- Smith Family Farm, Howellsville, N. C., 1960. A copy of a newspaper clipping and five images depicting the Walter Graham Smith Family Farm. Recognized as the ASC Farm Family of 1960. Howellsville, Robeson County, NC. c. 1960, PhC.68.1.203.1-6; Carolina Power and Light
- Electrical Appliances Installed in Residences in Goldsboro, N. C., 1968. Contact sheet of 11 frames depicting interior and exterior views of unidentified residences with new electrical appliances. Goldsboro, Wayne County, NC c. 1968. Original negatives included, PhC.68.1.204.1-7; Carolina Power and Light
- Agricultural Development Systems, Raleigh, NC Sumter, SC, 1968-73., PhC.68.1.205.1-126; Carolina Power and Light
  - Two views of an irrigation system in use over an unidentified crop., PhC.68.1.205.6-009; Carolina Power and Light
  - Agriculture Development, Two men are seen looking at a part of an irrigation system, examining a tobacco plant in a field, sitting at table looking at papers, and standing near a pool of water., PhC.68.1.205.6-022; Carolina Power and Light
  - Views of an irrigation system watering a crop of tobacco and several views of a CP&L exhibit outside of Dorton Arena., PhC.68.1.205.6-020; Carolina Power and Light
  - Twelve color images depicting a manure handling system., PhC.68.1.205.6-030; Carolina Power and Light
  - Images depicting a Sumter, South Carolina agricultural demonstration project. Irrigation systems, crops, CP&L employees and equipment are seen., PhC.68.1.205.6-006; Carolina Power and Light
  - Agricultural development photos depicting a pest/bug catcher apparatus being demonstrated. c. 1968-1973, PhC.68.1.205.6-007; Carolina Power and Light
- Agricultural Exhibits, N. C. State Fair at Raleigh, 1969-74. Interior and exterior views of Carolina Power and Light Company and agricultural related exhibits at the North Carolina State Fair in Raleigh. Interior and exterior pictures of exhibits in and around Dorton Arena. Men, women and children are seen interacting with exhibits. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1969-1974, PhC.68.1.206.1-168; Carolina Power and Light
- Finer Farm, Columbus County, NC c. 1969. Four images depicting cotton and tobacco production on the Finer Farm, Columbus County, NC. A crop of tobacco is seen, a very close view of a cotton boll, and an unidentified man holds a very large tobacco leaf. c. 1969, PhC.68.1.207.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Exhibit, Raleigh, NC c. 1970. Two views of a Carolina Power and Light exhibit. Men and women are seen interacting with the exhibit consisting of a trailer with walkways around it featuring information and interactives. c. 1970, PhC.68.1.208.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Future Farmers of America, Agricultural Development, Land Judging c. 1970-1973. Future Farmers of America are seen in classrooms, in land judging demonstrations and other activities related to agricultural development. c. 1970-1973, PhC.68.1.209.1-123; Carolina Power and Light
- Unidentified Poultry Processing Plant c. 1971. Interior views of an unidentified poultry processing plant. Cleaning and packaging process of eggs is depicted. A small boy is seen reaching into a pail of grain to feed hundreds of baby chicks seen at his feet. c. 1971, PhC.68.1.210.1-39; Carolina Power and Light
- Unidentified Turkey Farm, Goldsboro, NC c. 1972. Exterior views of an unidentified turkey farm in Goldsboro, NC. Hundreds of turkeys are seen in an open field. Three men are seen among them. Goldsboro, Wayne County, NC c. 1972, PhC.68.1.211.1-19; Carolina Power and Light
- Agricultural Engineering Development c. 1972 and 1973. Photographs depicting various agricultural engineering development equipment and relating projects. Irrigation systems, water heaters, grain dryers, time clocks, air conditioners, etc. c. 1972-1973, PhC.68.1.212.1-70; Carolina Power and Light
- Greenhouses, Horticultural Research Station, Clinton, NC c. 1973. Photographs depicting electricity on farms and the use of greenhouses in agricultural development at the Horticultural Crops Research Station in Clinton, Sampson County, NC c. April 1973, PhC.68.1.213.1-87; Carolina Power and Light
- Farm Materials Handling Show, Dorton Arena, Raleigh, N.C., 1974. Interior and exterior views of the Farm Materials Handling Show at Dorton Arena in Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1974, PhC.68.1.214.1-124; Carolina Power and Light
- Unidentified N. C. Farm at Night, c. 1974. Three night views of an unidentified North Carolina farm. A man is seen working on a tractor under an overhead light. c. 1974, PhC.68.1.215.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Representatives Visit Farm, Robeson County, NC c. 1970. Two photographs depicting Carolina Power and Light company representatives visiting an unidentified farm. A farmer and a representative are seen examining a panel box. Robeson County, NC c. 1970, PhC.68.1.216.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Farmer Operates New Front End Blade and Ditch Digger, c. 1975. A farmer is seen operating a front end blade and trench digger. Color photograph. c. 1975, PhC.68.1.217; Carolina Power and Light
- Irrigation Study on Unidentified Corn Farm c. 1973. Views of irrigated and regular corn fields and their yield on an unidentified farm. c. 1973, PhC.68.1.219.1-34; Carolina Power and Light
- Unidentified Peach Farm, ca. 1973. Two men are seen at an unidentified peach farm. They are seen around trees and examining peaches. c. 1973, PhC.68.1.218.1-11; Carolina Power and Light
- Cattle, Swine, and Silos on Farm, Columbus County, NC c. 1970. Five images depicting cattle, pigs, silos and other farm equipment on an unidentified farm. Possibly in Columbus County, NC c. 1970, PhC.68.1.220.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Farmers Posing with Tractors c. 1955. Approximately 20 farmers are seen posing in a line with tractors and other equipment. Possibly Robeson County, NC c. 1955, PhC.68.1.221; Carolina Power and Light
- Yadkin River Power Company, Unidentified Location c. 1923. Front exterior view of Yadkin River Power Company. Fifth Street in unidentified town. Electric fans can be seen in the window. c. 1923, PhC.68.1.223; Carolina Power and Light
- Yadkin River Power Company, Unidentified Location c. 1923. Front exterior view of Yadkin River Power Company. Unidentified location. c. 1923, PhC.68.1.222; Carolina Power and Light
- Wadesboro, NC, Storefront of the Yadkin River Power Company c. 1923. PhC68.1.224 Storefront of the Yadkin River Power Company Local Office in Wadesboro, NC at 117 North Greene Street. Lighting and other products can be seen displayed in the windows. Wadesboro, Anson County, NC c. 1916, PhC.68.1.224; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Carolina Power and Light Office, South Salisbury Street c. 1942. View of the offices of Carolina Power and Light on South Salisbury Street in Raleigh, NC. The back of the Durham Life Insurance Building is seen as well as a man standing by a car on the left side of frame. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c.1942, PhC.68.1.225; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Interior Views of Carolina Power and Light Office c. 1943. Five interior views of the corporate offices of Carolina Power and Light located in the Durham Life Insurance building in downtown Raleigh, NC. Shows customers and employees conducting business. Various promotional posters can be seen including one that reads, "New appliances will have to wait until victory". Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1943, PhC.68.1.226.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Carolina Power and Light Streetcar Barn Side View c. 1927. Carolina Power and Light streetcar barn located on West Street in Raleigh, NC is seen. Two streetcars are seen in the bay doors. Residential houses can be seen behind and beside the structure. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c.1927, PhC.68.1.227.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Carolina Power and Light Streetcar Barn Front View c. 1927. Front view of Carolina Power and Light streetcar barn located on West Street in Raleigh, NC is seen. Three streetcars are seen in the bay doors. Residential houses can be seen behind the structure. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c.1927, PhC.68.1.228.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Carolina Power and Light Streetcar Barn Interior View c. 1927. Interior view of the Carolina Power and Light streetcar barn located on West Street in Raleigh, NC. One streetcar is seen over repair dugout. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1927, PhC.68.1.229; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Carolina Power and Light General Garage Side View c. 1927. View of the Carolina Power and Light general garage from the corner of Harrington and Jones Streets in Raleigh, NC. c. 1927, PhC.68.1.230.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Carolina Power and Light General Garage Interior View c. 1927. Interior View of the Carolina Power and Light general garage on the corner of Harrington and Jones Streets in Raleigh, NC. Various work automobiles are seen inside the structure, all parked in an orderly fashion. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1927, PhC.68.1.231.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Carolina Power and Light General Garage Side View (West Street) c. 1927. Side view of the Carolina Power and Light general garage from the corner of West and Jones Streets in Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1927, PhC.68.1.232; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Carolina Power and Light General Garage Interior View c. 1927. Interior View of the Carolina Power and Light general garage on the corner of Harrington and Jones Streets in Raleigh, NC. Four work automobiles and two city buses are seen inside the structure. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1927, PhC.68.1.233; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Temporary Coal Storage, Raleigh Electric Company Power House c. 19??. View of the temporary coal storage for Raleigh Electric Company Powerhouse. The powerhouse can be seen in the background. Raleigh, Wake County, NC, PhC.68.1.234; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Fence Surrounds Electrical Tower at State Asylum c.1909. Two men are seen standing on either side of an electricity tower surrounded by a fence. Back of photo is captioned, "Raleigh-Buckhorn 60kv transmission line. Wire fence protection around tower in State Asylum grounds Raleigh 1909" Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1909, PhC.68.1.235; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Milburnie Line Generating Station c. 1904. Two men are seen, _____ Rich (left), Distribution Superintendent, and Harry Robbins, Power Plant Shift Operator. They are seen standing in front of an abandoned streetcar converted into a shack at the Milburnie line receiving station. Raleigh, NC, Wake County c. 1904, PhC.68.1.236; Carolina Power and Light
- Three Linemen Atop Power Pole, Circus or Fair c. 1910. Card photograph of three linemen seen atop a power pole at a circus or fair type of event. Tents are seen in background with people walking and standing around them. A horse is seen attached to a carriage and a man stands with his bicycle. Back of photograph is inscribed, "C.T. Biggers" c. 1910, PhC.68.1.237; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Carolina Power and Light Line Crew Martin and McDowell Streets c. 1916. A Carolina Power and Light line crew is seen posing for a picture as they hoist a power/light pole upright. Hotel Raleigh is seen directly behind the group of approximately 2 dozen men (white and African American). Two horses are seen hooked up to the piece of machinery hoisting the light pole upright. Corner of Martin and McDowell Streets. Circle Pharmacy occupies the corner storefront. Raleigh, Wake County, NC 5 July 1916, PhC.68.1.238.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Goldsboro, NC, J.M. Thomas Line Crew With First Two-Ton Truck, 1919. J. M. Thomas line crew with Carolina Power and Light. 15 men pose in front of the Goldsboro CP&L office. The men are seen posing with the company's first 2-ton truck. Sam Lee Laundry is seen in the background. Goldsboro, NC, c.1919?, PhC.68.1.239.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Linemen Seen With Truck in Front of Garage on Harrington Street c. 1920. Nine linemen and two formally dressed men are seen posing in front of a Carolina Power and Light truck parked in front of the CP&L garage located on Harrington Street in Raleigh, NC. c. 1920, PhC.68.1.240.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Safety Demonstration, Eastern NC c. 1926. Three individual safety demonstration scenes of linemen performing what appears to be a rescue operation drill from the top of a power pole. 15 September 1926, PhC.68.1.241.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- C.W. Gaddy Line Crew, Carolina Power and Light, Zebulon, N.C., ca. 1920. C.W. Gaddy Electric Line Crew is seen posing with a Corbitt truck and trailer. Nine white men are seen posing with the truck and 5 African American men are seen sitting on electric poles on the trailer of the truck. Zebulon, NC c. 1920, PhC.68.1.242.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Photograph, Light Bulb and Invoice c. 1928. Still life of a photograph depicting six men posing with a Carolina Power and Light truck, a lightbulb (lit) and a CP&L invoice. c. 1928, PhC.68.1.243; Carolina Power and Light
- Black Mountain, NC, Carolina Power and Light Linemen with Truck c. 1932. Two views of Carolina Power and Light linemen posing with a company truck (Mack) outside of Gragg's Photo Studio in Black Mountain, NC. c. 1932, PhC.68.1.244.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Line Crew Group Picture c. 1928. Several Carolina Power and Light Line Crews (approximately 35 men) are seen standing in a line for a group picture. The line crew in PhC68.1.240 is seen in the group picture. They are standing in front of three Carolina Power and Light service trucks. Possibly on Harrington Street in Raleigh, NC. Wake County c. 1928, PhC.68.1.245; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Linemen Changing Insulators c. 1932. Carolina Power and Light linemen are seen changing insulators atop a power pole in a rural area. Photograph is inscribed, "Lineman changing insulators with line hot on one of our LIKV distribution circuits. The tools are good for 10000 volts per foot.", PhC.68.1.246; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Line Crew In Unidentified Location c. 1932. Close view of a group of 6 Carolina Power and Light linemen posing for a group picture outdoors. Unidentified location c. 1932, PhC.68.1.247; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Lineman on Pole, Unidentified Location c. 1932. A lineman for Carolina Power and Light is seen working at the top of a large electric pole in a rural area. c. 1932, PhC.68.1.248; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Linemen on Pole During Thunderstorm c. 1935. Two Carolina Power and Light linemen are seen atop an electric pole as a bolt of lightning strikes behind them in a thunderstorm. c. 1935, PhC.68.1.249; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Linemen in Intracoastal Waterway, Wilmington, NC c. 1956. Four scenes of a Carolina Power and Light lineman crew working in the intracoastal waterway. They are seen unloading a small boat from the top of a truck, J. L. Hexsen is seen fixing a streetlight in Wilmington, and driving the boat. Wilmington, NC c. 1956, PhC.68.1.250.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Linemen Erect Utility Pole, Asheville, NC c. 1965. Four Carolina Power and Light linemen are seen working together to erect a utility pole in Asheville, NC. Pictured are Troy Bouks, Denneth White, V. V. McKinney and John Stevson. Asheville, Buncombe County, NC c. 1965, PhC.68.1.251; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Linemen With Transformers c.1950s. Nine Carolina Power and Light line workers pose beneath three large transformers. c. June 1970 UPDATE: 25 March 2015, Close examination of this photo reveals that it was taken c. 1950s, not June 1970. The previous date refers to a date written on the back of the print referencing the photo's use in a June 1970 CP&L history piece in a newsletter., PhC.68.1.252; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Linemen Haywood/Mitchell Counties, NC c. 1935. Five views of Carolina Power and Light Company Linemen Erecting New Lines at the City Substation, with utility truck, hoisting a pole in the ground, and a view of transformers after installation at the Waynesville Furniture Company. Hazelwood, Haywood County, NC Also shows linemen loading poles in Spruce Pine, Mitchell County, NC c. 1935, PhC.68.1.253.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Linemen in Asheville, NC c. 1965. Carolina Power and Light linemen are seen high above the ground working on electrical wires in Asheville, NC. V. V. McKenny is seen. c. 1965, PhC.68.1.254.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- C.W. Gaddy Line Crew, Unidentified Location, c. 1926. C. W. Gaddy and his line crew are pictured standing in front of a Corbitt truck. Several African Americans are among the line crew. Unidentified location c. 1926, PhC.68.1.255; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Work Crews, LaGrange, Wadesboro, N.C., 1927-1937. Nine photographs of Carolina Power and Light line and work crews with trucks at LaGrange, Lenoir County and Wadesboro, Anson County, NC. c. 1927-1937, PhC.68.1.256.1-8; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Carolina Power and Light Line Crews at General Garage c. 1928. Twenty two Carolina Power and Light workmen are seen standing in front of a utility truck at the General Garage in Raleigh, NC. Wake County c. 1928 1928., PhC.68.1.257; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Linemen Wire House c. 1937. Several Carolina Power and Light linemen are seen wiring a house. Unidentified location. c. 1937, PhC.68.1.258; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, J.T. Dorman Line Crew c. 1909. J. T. Dorman Line Crew is pictured. Dorman is construction superintendent for the Raleigh Buckhorn 60000 volt transmission line. Raleigh, Wake County, NC. c. 1909, PhC.68.1.259; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Line Crews c. 1935. Four group portraits of Carolina Power and Light linemen. Each group portrait contains 3-6 linemen. One group portrait of all linemen seen in previous separate group portraits. They are posing in front of an unidentified building. c. 1935, PhC.68.1.260; Carolina Power and Light
- Views of Carolina Power and Light Linemen c. 1928-1950., PhC.68.1.261.1-11; Carolina Power and Light
  - Views of Carolina Power and Light Linemen c. 1928-1950. Linemen are seen at what appears to be a training exercise. Short power pole is seen with workers surrounding., PhC.68.1.261.1; Carolina Power and Light
  - A man is seen in a yard at an industrial building driving a forklift., PhC.68.1.261.2; Carolina Power and Light
  - Three men are seen standing at the front of an automobile. Captioned, "Car fender makes a good table to study map for right of way clearing. Left to right are H. O. Drennan, supervisor of row clearing, L. N. Massey, his inspector, and the operator of the bulldozer shown in another picture.", PhC.68.1.261.3; Carolina Power and Light
  - Two men are seen at the top of an electric pole. Possibly training exercise., PhC.68.1.261.4; Carolina Power and Light
  - Six unidentified linemen are seen posing in front of a work truck, PhC.68.1.261.5; Carolina Power and Light
  - L. D. Bailey's line crew. Left to right are, J. A. Kelley, E. Patterson, P. H. Odom, H. T. Jackson, L. D. Bailey, R. P Anderson. They are posing in front of a work truck. c. 1928, PhC.68.1.261.6; Carolina Power and Light
  - Unidentified line crew inspects R.O.W. before wiring at unidentified location. Appears to be a training exercise. c. 1946, PhC.68.1.261.7; Carolina Power and Light
  - Line crew is seen at what appears to be a training exercise., PhC.68.1.261.8; Carolina Power and Light
  - Crew installs streetlight above Sanford Auto Supply in Sanford, NC. c. 1947, PhC.68.1.261.9; Carolina Power and Light
  - Unidentified lineman is seen at the top of a light pole. c. 1950, PhC.68.1.261.10; Carolina Power and Light
  - Unidentified crew clears right of way at unidentified location. c. 1946, PhC.68.1.261.11; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Transformer Crew with Truck c.1940. Two views of an unidentified Carolina Power and Light transformer crew with truck at an unidentified location. c. 1940, PhC.68.1.262.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Linemen, Right-of-Way Crews, Asheville, NC c. 1948., PhC.68.1.263.1-12; Carolina Power and Light
  - Carolina Power and Light Linemen, Right-of-Way Crews, Asheville, NC c. 1948. Crew is seen installing line on right of way near Asheville, NC. c. 1948, PhC.68.1.263.1; Carolina Power and Light
  - Crew is seen installing line on right of way near Asheville, NC. c. 1948, PhC.68.1.263.2; Carolina Power and Light
  - Foreman, M. R. Calloway with truck. Asheville, NC c. 1948, PhC.68.1.263.3; Carolina Power and Light
  - Foreman, M. R. Calloway in Asheville, NC c. 1948, PhC.68.1.263.4; Carolina Power and Light
  - Two unidentified linemen atop electric pole. Asheville, NC c. 1948, PhC.68.1.263.5; Carolina Power and Light
  - Linemen hoist electric pole with work truck. Left to right, Troy Brooks, Kenneth White, V. V. McKinney, John Stevson. Asheville, NC c. 1948, PhC.68.1.263.6; Carolina Power and Light
  - Earl Haynes is seen taking water break beside work truck. Asheville, NC c. 1954, PhC.68.1.263.7; Carolina Power and Light
  - Earl Haynes and Kenneth White are seen digging with shovels. Asheville, NC c.1954, PhC.68.1.263.8; Carolina Power and Light
  - Troy Brooks, John Stevenson, V. V. McKinney, Kenneth White, M. R. Calloway are seen installing electric power pole. Asheville, NC c. 1948, PhC.68.1.263.9; Carolina Power and Light
  - Two unidentified linemen atop power pole. c. 1948, PhC.68.1.263.10; Carolina Power and Light
  - Four unidentified linemen are seen preparing to "Cross Arms" with two electric poles. c. 1948, PhC.68.1.263.11; Carolina Power and Light